<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<articles>
    <article>
        <title>Man Charged Following Assault at Downtown Residence</title>
        <image>https://media-cdn.socastsrm.com/wordpress/wp-content/blogs.dir/900/files/2020/05/RNC-Car-2016.jpg</image>
        <description>A man has been charged after an incident at a home in downtown St. John’s.

            Police were called to a disturbance around 7:00 yesterday evening to find that someone had been assaulted.

            A 62-year-old man was taken into custody on charges of assault and assault with a weapon.</description>
        <date>2024-12-10</date>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Alleged Impaired ATV Driver Refuses To Go Quietly, Charges Ensue</title>
        <image>https://media-cdn.socastsrm.com/wordpress/wp-content/blogs.dir/900/files/2024/09/new-rcmp-detachment-marystown-burin.jpg</image>
        <description>A 30-year-old man suspected of impaired driving has a lot more on his plate after allegedly getting into a skirmish with police.

            Burin Peninsula RCMP were called out around 6:45 p.m. Sunday regarding a potential impaired driver on an ATV in Little Bay.

            Police found the man a short time later with the machine, but he refused to go quietly and was charged with resisting arrest after allegedly assaulting the officers.

            He’s also accused of refusing to provide breath samples after arriving at the RCMP detachment.

            On top of that, police discovered he might also be responsible for a previous incident, for which he was charged with uttering threats and assault with a weapon.

            The man’s licence was suspended and, in total, he’s now facing two counts of assaulting a police officer, and one count each of resisting arrest, impaired driving, refusing to comply with a breath demand, assault with a weapon and uttering threats.

            The suspect’s name was not released.</description>
        <date>2024-12-09</date>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Government Stands Firm as MUN Faces Financial Strain</title>
        <image>https://media-cdn.socastsrm.com/wordpress/wp-content/blogs.dir/900/files/2020/03/MUN.jpg</image>
        <description>oth the Memorial University Faculty Association and the Students Union are calling for government assistance to help the university with a financial shortfall caused by a drop in international enrolment – but that doesn’t look likely.

            The university called a surprise news conference on Friday to outline measures taken to address a projected $9.5 million shortfall from a 5.4 per cent drop in international student enrolment.

            The university is putting a pause on most hiring with certain exceptions, introducing restrictions to carry over funds, and developing a new budget model.

            That’s led to calls for the government to step in to help the university with its fiscal situation and to address concerns like millions of dollars in deferred maintenance.

            In a statement provided to VOCM News, Education Minister Krista Lynn Howell says Memorial University is an autonomous organization accountable for its own fiscal policies and practices. The province says it’s confident that MUN is making decisions and implementing measures that will have the desired outcome while minimizing the impact on students and staff.

            The provincial government provided an allocation of $400 million to the university in the last budget. More than 70 per cent of the university’s operating revenue comes directly from the province – among the highest in the country.</description>
        <date>2024-12-09</date>
    </article>
    <article>
        <title>Backhoe Bandits Strike Again: Esso Gas Station Heavily Damaged in Break-In</title>
        <image>https://media-cdn.socastsrm.com/wordpress/wp-content/blogs.dir/900/files/2024/12/backhoe-bandits-1.png</image>
        <description>Backhoe bandits have struck another business in the metro region.

         The Esso gas station near Kenmount Terrace has been closed and barred off since late last week.

         The RNC have confirmed that they responded to a break and enter, in which a piece of heavy equipment was used, just before 5 a.m. last Friday morning (November 29th).

         The building has been heavily damaged as a result.

         The heavy equipment was seen travelling up Kenmount Road near Canada Post just before 4 a.m. that day.

          Anyone with information is asked to contact the RNC or Crime Stoppers.</description>
        <date>2024-12-04</date>
    </article>
</articles>
